Bodman Family Papers, 1687-1980
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Bodman family papers
1687-1980 [ongoing]
1840-1920
Bodman family
MS 232
42 boxes (24 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Papers cover 10 generations of the Bodman family, from small town New England farmers to Midwestern bankers and grain elevator owners. They are an extremely rich source for the study of U.S. social history, providing a long-term look at an American family. The earliest material documents rural New England life. Family and business correspondence documents the daily life and business ventures in the Midwest. Materials include diaries, photographs, writings, and papers relating to the service during World War I of Herbert Luther Sr., and Theodora (Dunham) Bodman.
The history of this line of the Bodman family in the United States can be traced to John and Sarah Bodman, English immigrants to the Massachusetts Bay Colony during the Great Migration of 1629-40. The Bodman Family Papers trace their descendants beginning with their son Joseph.
Joseph Bodman was raised in Boston. He first saw the Connecticut River Valley of Massachusetts in 1675 as a soldier in King Philip's War. He returned to the area to homestead in the early 1680s, eventually settling in Hatfield, where the family was to remain for almost 100 years. In the early 1770s, three of Joseph's great-grandsons left Hatfield for the new township of Williamsburg. Seventeenth and eighteenth century Bodmans supported themselves by combining artisanry with subsistence farming. In the nineteenth century the scarcity of good land and the uncertainties of farming in New England led some Bodmans to join the westward migration settling in New York, Ohio, and Illinois. Those that remained in the East tried new enterprises such as factory production at a sawmill and tannery in Williamsburg, shop keeping in Charlemont, and banking in Conway and Northampton.
Beginning in the 1850s, investments in Illinois land led to family involvement in banking and grain merchandising that was to last well into the twentieth century. The firm of Milmine, Bodman and Co., founded in 1861 by Edward Cushman Bodman, grew from small-town bank (in Bement, Illinois) to international grain brokerage by the early 1890s.
In the mid-1970s, four Bodman cousins took an interest in their family's history and researched and wrote A Bodman Chronicle (1980). This book provides much biographical detail on Bodmans through the nineteenth century, plus genealogical charts and records for all known descendants of John and Sarah Bodman and should be consulted as a supplement to this description.
The Bodman Family Papers consist of 24 linear feet of biographical material, correspondence, diaries, financial and business records, genealogical research material, legal documents, memorabilia, photographs, writings, and miscellaneous papers of ten generations of Bodman family members dating from 1687 to 1980. The bulk of the material dates from the 1840s through the 1910s. The papers are an extremely rich source for the study of United States social history, providing a long-term look at an American family.
The earliest material (1680s-1830s) documents rural New England life primarily through financial records and legal instruments. Beginning in the 1830s such material is augmented by family and business correspondence documenting daily life and business ventures in New England and the Midwest.
By the 1880s, with few Bodmans remaining in New England, the geographical center of the papers shifts to New York and the Midwest. For the period 1880-1920, family correspondence makes up a significant portion of the material, while business and financial records appear in much greater bulk than in the preceding generations, particularly in the papers of Edward Cushman Bodman (generation VI). These materials are supplemented with diaries, memorabilia, photographs, writings, and papers relating to the service during World War I of Herbert Luther, Sr., and Theodora (Dunham) Bodman (generation VII).
The largest portion of the material from the period 1920 to 1980 is genealogy and family correspondence. In addition, there are a number of line-a-day and travel diaries, photographs, scrapbooks and other memorabilia, plus personal financial records.
Family history has long been of interest to the Bodmans. Genealogical research material and notes can be found in the papers of Clara Philena Bodman (generation VI), Ida (Berdan) Bodman (generation VI), George Milmine Bodman (generation VII), Henry Edward Bodman (generation VII), Henry Taylor Bodman (generation VIII), and Herbert Luther, Jr. and Ellen-Fairbanks (Diggs) Bodman (generation VIII).
The papers are arranged by generation. Within each generation, papers of individuals, groups of siblings, or married couples are filed alphabetically by first name of Bodman descendant. Where applicable, papers of married couples are divided into three sequences beginning with common property, which is followed by papers of the Bodman descendant and then those of his or her spouse. The material is arranged by type.
Photographs and negatives are filed in separate sequences following the papers. Images of or by Bodmans are arranged alphabetically. Other images are arranged by subject.
Oversize items are stored separately. Removal sheets are filed throughout the papers and a listing of the contents of the oversize boxes is available as part of the folder-title list following.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Bodman Family Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Additional Formats
Selections from the Bodman Family Papers can be viewed in the Web exhibit Across the Generations: Exploring U.S. History through Family Papers.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected.
History of the Collection
The majority of the material making up the Bodman Family Papers was the gift of Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr. and Ellen-Fairbanks (Diggs) Bodman in 1985. Additions to the papers came from Elizabeth Holden in 1985 and from Robert Edgar Bodman and Henry Taylor Bodman in 1987.
Search Terms
Family--United States--History--Sources; Massachusetts--History--Sources; Middle West--History--Sources; New England--History--Sources; Upper class families--United States--History--Sources; World War, 1914-1918--France--Personal narratives, American; Bodman family; Courtship--United States--History--Sources; United States--Social life and customs--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
See also the Dunham Family Papers. Researchers should note that there is material related to the Dunham and Bodman families in both collections and that there are cross-references to the Bodman Family Papers throughout the Dunham Family Papers inventory. The papers of Theodora Dunham Bodman are mostly located in the Bodman Family Papers except for her correspondence to her parents (filed under Mary Dows Dunham).
- GENERATION I
  - Joseph Bodman (1659-1711)
    - Account book, 1701-11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Account book [and transcription, 1976], 1701-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Account book [and transcription of sermon notes, 1976], 1701-11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1687-1712 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- GENERATION II
  - Manoah Bodman (1692-1759): receipts, deed, inventory of estate, 1715-59 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Samuel (1695-1764) and Martha (Warner) Bodman (dates unknown)
    - Samuel
      - Account book, 1705-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Account book, Hatfield church, 1736-46 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Index to accounts (?), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1717-69, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Receipts - settlement of estate of Manoah Bodman, 1759-60 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Martha: will (?), 1788 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Samuel and William Bodman: deeds, receipts, 1717-68 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William Bodman (1698- 1723): note of debt, fragment, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- GENERATION III
  - Joseph Bodman (1731-1818)
    - Account books, 1776-1802 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Account book, 1783-95, [see M61 for microfilm] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1759-1818 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Joseph, Samuel, and William Bodman:receipt, pew assign, 1785, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Samuel Bodman (1736-1827)
    - Constable business, 1770-77 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1772-1803 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Deeds, 1778-1812 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Estate of Jesse Wild
      - Account book, 1761-62 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1756-1811 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1781-1812, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Notes of debt, 1770-1820 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Receipts, 1775-1816 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Samuel and William Bodman
    - Deeds, 1772-73 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous papers re estate of Samuel (1695-1764), 1776-87 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - William Bodman (1741-1835): miscellaneous papers, 1772-1827 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- GENERATION IV
  - Joseph Bodman (1772-1847)
    - Bodman & Phillips: deed, indenture, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Deeds, 1799-l844 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1800-45 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Receipts, 1842 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Luther, Sr. (1780-1861) and Clarissa (Day) (1787-1864) Bodman
    - Correspondence
      - Elam and Jerusha Bodman, 1837-65 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Lewis Bodman, 1833-35, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Lewis, Luther, Jr., and (Clarissa) Angeline Bodman, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Luther, Jr., and Philena (Hawks) Bodman, 1834-35, 1844-45 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Samuel Bodman, 1838-44, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Luther, Sr.
      - Account book (sawmill), 1836-40 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Correspondence
        - Joseph Bodman, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - Salmon Munson, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1813-35 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Clarissa:correspondence from (Clarissa) Angeline Bodman, 1845, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Manoah Bodman (1764-1850): miscellaneous papers, 1805-20 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Theophilus Bodman (1793-1838): deed, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- GENERATION V
  - (Clarissa) Angeline (Bodman) Hawks (1831-64): miscellaneous papers, 1851-52, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Elam Bodman (1812-1901): correspondence, Oliver Bodman, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Joseph Bodman (1819-97)
    - Certificate from Grand Masonic Lodge of Massachusetts, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence
      - Elam and Sarah Ann Bodman, 1851-60 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Lewis Bodman, 1846, 1852, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Luther Bodman, Jr., 1851-61, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Samuel Bodman, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - (Clarissa) Angeline (Bodman) Hawks, 1846, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - Miscellaneous, 1843-61, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Joseph Lyman (1810-57) and Cordelia (Hubbard) (c.1814-1900) Bodman: miscellaneous papers, 1848-57 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lewis (1809-86) and Emily (Nash) (1819-90) Bodman
    - Lewis
      - Correspondence
        - Charles Goodwin Bodman, 1867, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 56)
        - Elam Bodman, 1839-41 (Box 3, Folder 57)
        - Emily (Nash) Bodman, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 58)
        - Frank Hubbard Bodman, 1868-75 (Box 3, Folder 59)
        - Joseph Bodman, 1854-73 (Box 3, Folder 60)
        - Lewis Henry Bodman, 1866-75 (Box 3, Folder 61-64)
        - Luther Bodman, Jr., 1862-75 (Box 3, Folder 65)
        - Samuel Bodman, 1866-75 (Box 3, Folder 66)
        - Samuel Luther Bodman, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 67)
        - Sereno Bodman, 1867-68 (Box 3, Folder 68)
        - Mary Sylvia (Bodman) Canterbury, 1867, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 69)
        - Miscellaneous family, 1869, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 70)
        - Miscellaneous non-family, 1848-72 (Box 3, Folder 71)
        - To unidentified brothers, 1852-79 (Box 3, Folder 72)
        - Financial, 1863-75 (Box 3, Folder 73)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1844-73 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Emily
      - Correspondence
        - Lewis Henry Bodman, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 75)
        - Frank Hubbard and Clara (Walker) Bodman, 1872-75 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Lewis and Luther Bodman, Jr.: account book, L & L Bodman Co., 1868-71 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Luther, Jr. (1814-47) and Philena (Hawks) (1817-94) Bodman
    - Correspondence
      - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1852-57 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Ellen (Bodman) and Charles Parkhurst, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - (Luther) Whitney Bodman, 1856-58, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Wills, inventory of estate, 1884-96 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Luther, Jr.
      - Correspondence
        - Business, miscellaneous, 1848-53 (Box 3, Folder 82-83)
        - Business, miscellaneous, 1856-69, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 84-85)
        - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1856, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 86)
        - Elam Bodman, 1838-56 (Box 4, Folder 87)
        - Joseph Bodman, 1845-59 (Box 4, Folder 88)
        - Lewis Bodman, 1846-59 (Box 4, Folder 89-91)
        - Philena (Hawks) Bodman, 1845-56 (Box 4, Folder 92)
        - James A. Hawkes, 1848-58 (Box 4, Folder 93)
        - William A. Hawks, 1855-60 (Box 4, Folder 94)
        - Ellen (Bodman) Parkhurst, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 95)
        - Miscellaneous, 1864-68 (Box 4, Folder 96)
        - To unidentified brothers, 1879-80 (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - Business papers, miscellaneous, 1841-60, undated (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - Invoices and receipts, 1852-55, undated (Box 4, Folder 99-101)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1834-1879 (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - Railroad bills of lading, 1852-54 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Philena
      - Cookbook, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - Correspondence
        - (Clarissa) Angeline Bodman, 1851-54, undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
        - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1854-1857 (Box 4, Folder 106)
        - Emily Caroline (Nash) Bodman and daughter, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 107)
        - Luther Bodman, Jr., 1848-68, undated (Box 4, Folder 108)
        - (Luther) Whitney Bodman, 1857, undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
        - Susan (Kingsley) Bodman, 1855-56 (Box 4, Folder 110)
        - William A. Hawks, 1853-60 (Box 4, Folder 111)
        - William Mayhew, 1836-52 (Box 4, Folder 112)
        - Ellen (Bodman) Parkhurst, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 113)
        - Miscellaneous, 1832-57, undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
        - Silas and Rebecca Hawks, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - Writings, 1838, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Oliver Booth Bodman (1825-50)
    - Correspondence
      - Albert Holmes Bodman, 1844-46 (Box 4, Folder 117-119)
      - (Clarissa) Angeline Bodman, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Elam Bodman, 1846 (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - Joseph Bodman, 1850 (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - Miscellaneous, 1847-49 (Box 4, Folder 123)
      - To unidentified brothers, 1846, undated (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Samuel Bodman (1807-82)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous, 1832-55 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - To unidentified brothers, 1852, 1857, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
- GENERATION VI
  - Albert Holmes Bodman (1826-85)
    - Chicago Daily Tribune column [photocopy], Mar-Nov 1863 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - "Episodes of the Rebellion," speech [photocopy], undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - "In Sight of Vicksburg," diary [photocopy], Feb-Mar 1863 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Alice (Pratt) Bodman (1860-1934): diary [transcription], 1883-85 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Clara Philena Bodman (1859-1951)
    - Art Club, 1888, undated (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Autograph book, 1855-1942 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Correspondence
      - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - George Milmine Bodman, undated (Box 5, Folder 134)
      - Ida (Berdan) Bodman, 1878, 1884, undated (Box 5, Folder 135)
      - (Luther) Whitney and Grace (Smith) Bodman, 1884-93, undated (Box 5, Folder 136-137)
      - Philena (Hawks) Bodman, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 138)
      - Annie C. Bridgman, 1884-1901 (Box 5, Folder 139)
      - Howard Bridgman, 1886-94, undated (Box 5, Folder 140)
      - George Washington Cable, 1894-1906 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      - Mary Bryant Daniels, 1885-92 (Box 5, Folder 142)
      - Mary Ellis, 1876-95, undated (Box 5, Folder 143)
      - Mary A. Frost, undated (Box 5, Folder 144)
      - Hawks family, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 145)
      - T.H. Hawks family, 1885-1906 (Box 5, Folder 146)
      - Jeannette Mabie, undated (Box 5, Folder 147)
      - Charles and Ellen (Bodman) Parkhurst, 1883-1901, undated (Box 5, Folder 148)
      - Rev. J.E. Rankin, 1890-99 (Box 5, Folder 149)
      - Delia Stearns, 1886-87 (Box 5, Folder 150)
      - Akuri _____, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 151)
      - Alfred _____, 1904, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 152)
      - Re genealogy, 1900-38, undated (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Miscellaneous, 1881-1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 154-156)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1859-1924 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - Edward Cushman (1840-1917) and Ida (Berdan) (1855-1937) Bodman
    - Correspondence
      - George Milmine Bodman, 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 158)
      - Herbert Luther Bodman, 1897-1908 (Box 6, Folder 159-160)
    - Marriage license, 8 Jan 1878 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Edward
      - Correspondence - Family
        - Arthur E. Baker, 1888-1912 (Box 6, Folder 162)
        - Fred Berdan, 1893-99 (Box 6, Folder 163)
        - John M. Berdan, 1895-1907, undated (Box 6, Folder 164-165)
        - Mary E. Berdan, 1888-1904 (Box 6, Folder 166)
        - Pamela Berdan, 1886-1912 (Box 6, Folder 167)
        - Peter F. Berdan, 1885-86 (Box 6, Folder 168)
        - Clara Philena Bodman, 1886-1913, undated (Box 6, Folder 169-170)
        - Frederick Harlan Bodman, 1893-1904, undated (Box 6, Folder 171)
        - George Milmine Bodman, 1893-1913, undated (Box 6, Folder 172)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, 1895-1913 (Box 6, Folder 173-175)
        - Ida (Berdan) Bodman, 1886-96, undated (Box 6, Folder 176-178)
        - Luther Bodman, Jr., 1885-86, undated (Box 7, Folder 179)
        - (Luther) Whitney Bodman, 1885-99 (Box 7, Folder 180-198)
        - (Luther) Whitney Bodman, 1901-13, undated (Box 8, Folder 199-214)
        - Marjorie Bodman, undated (Box 8, Folder 215)
        - Carroll Dunham, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 216)
        - Fred W. Hawkes, 1896-98 (Box 8, Folder 217)
        - Hawks family, 1891-99, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 218)
        - Albert and Mary Herter, 1910-14, undated (Box 8, Folder 219)
        - Charles and Ellen (Bodman) Parkhurst, 1885-1913, undated (Box 8, Folder 220-221)
        - Julia Rodgers, 1911, undated (Box 9, Folder 222)
        - Oliver Rodgers, 1886-1902 (Box 9, Folder 223-229)
        - Walter G. Shepard, 1888-1905 (Box 9, Folder 230)
        - Miscellaneous, 1880-1911, undated (Box 9, Folder 231)
      - Correspondence - General
        - A, 1886-1913 (Box 9, Folder 232-233)
        - Adams Memorial Presbyterian Church, 1904-11 (Box 9, Folder 234)
        - C. Auchard Real Estate and Loan Agent, 1886 (Box 9, Folder 235)
        - B, 1886-1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 236-238)
        - Brooklyn Trust Co., 1899-1904 (Box 9, Folder 239)
        - E.O. Brown & Co./Brown & Dodge, 1888-93 (Box 9, Folder 240)
        - A.S. Burr, 1885-1911 (Box 10, Folder 241-253)
        - A.S. Burr: bills, receipts, accounts, 1886-88 (Box 10, Folder 254-256)
        - C, 1886-1913, undated (Box 10, Folder 257-258)
        - George Washington Cable, 1899-1903 (Box 10, Folder 259)
        - George Chase, 1891-96 (Box 10, Folder 260)
        - City National Bank (Holdredge, NB), 1910-13 (Box 11, Folder 261)
        - City National Bank (Springfield, MA), 1888 (Box 11, Folder 262)
        - Cochran & Walsh, 1886-95, undated (Box 11, Folder 263-268)
        - Commercial Light and Power, 1896-1901 (Box 11, Folder 269)
        - Cooksey and Stebbins, 1901-13 (Box 11, Folder 270-271)
        - D, 1886-1912 (Box 11, Folder 272)
        - Davis Bar Harbor Buckboard Co., 1903-10 (Box 11, Folder 273)
        - E, 1888-1910, undated (Box 11, Folder 274)
        - F, 1888-1911, undated (Box 11, Folder 275)
        - Farmers National Bank, 1893-1912 (Box 11, Folder 276)
        - First National Bank (Duluth, MN), 1895-1913 (Box 11, Folder 277)
        - First National Bank (Toledo, OH), 1886-91 (Box 11, Folder 278)
        - Flandrau & Co., 1898-1905 (Box 11, Folder 279)
        - Forge House, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 280)
        - G, 1887-1912 (Box 11, Folder 281)
        - Genesee Fruit Co., 1896-1902 (Box 11, Folder 282)
        - H, 1886-1912, undated (Box 11, Folder 283-284)
        - Hampshire County National Bank, 1888-99, undated (Box 12, Folder 285)
        - Hampshire Marble Co., 1887-88 (Box 12, Folder 286)
        - N. Haughton and Co., 1886-93 (Box 12, Folder 287)
        - Michael Hennessy, 1904-05, undated (Box 12, Folder 288)
        - Hoffman Arms, 1893 (Box 12, Folder 289)
        - Hunt, Evans and Co., 1888-99, undated (Box 12, Folder 290-293)
        - International Trust Co., 1911 (Box 12, Folder 294)
        - J, 1893-1913 (Box 12, Folder 295)
        - K, 1886-1913, undated (Box 12, Folder 296)
        - Kingsley, Mabon and Co., 1893-1905 (Box 12, Folder 297)
        - R.B. Knox and Co., 1900-13 (Box 12, Folder 298-304)
        - F.A. Kumler Real Estate Office, 1886-1902 (Box 12, Folder 305)
        - L, 1888-1913 (Box 12, Folder 306)
        - Laidlow and Co., 1905-13 (Box 12, Folder 307)
        - Cyrus J. Lawrence and Sons, 1910-12, undated (Box 12, Folder 308)
        - William E. Lucas, 1891-99, undated (Box 13, Folder 309-320)
        - Lymansville Co., 1911-12 (Box 13, Folder 321)
        - M, 1886-1913, undated (Box 13, Folder 322-323)
        - Madison Square Church, 1893-1911 (Box 13, Folder 324-326)
        - Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1886-1912 (Box 13, Folder 327)
        - McConaughy Grain Co., 1905-12 (Box 13, Folder 328-330)
        - McKim, Mead & White, 1904-10 (Box 13, Folder 331)
        - W.B. Meikle, City Loans, 1888 (Box 13, Folder 332)
        - Milmine, Bodman and Co.
          - General, 1888-1912 (Box 14, Folder 333)
          - William H. Kemp, 1901-13 (Box 14, Folder 334-335)
          - C.W. McConaughy, 1898-1904 (Box 14, Folder 336-339)
          - Douglas Miller, 1904-11 (Box 14, Folder 340)
          - C.E. Milmine, 1896-1913 (Box 14, Folder 341)
          - George Milmine, 1885-96 (Box 14, Folder 342)
          - Sidney Mitchell, 1904-05 (Box 14, Folder 343)
          - E.H. Phelps, 1886-1902 (Box 14, Folder 344-347)
          - William Valiant, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 348)
          - Miscellaneous papers, 1886-1901, undated (Box 14, Folder 349)
        - Jas. H. Milne, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 350)
        - Minnesota Loan and Trust Co., 1888-91 (Box 14, Folder 35l)
        - N, 1888-1913 (Box 14, Folder 352)
        - Clarence M. Noble Real Estate and Insurance, 1894-98 (Box 14, Folder 353)
        - Northern National Bank, 1885-1910, undated (Box 14, Folder 354)
        - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1893-1910 (Box 14, Folder 355)
        - O, 1891-1905 (Box 14, Folder 356)
        - P, 1888-1913 (Box 14, Folder 357)
        - Procter and Co., 1893-1912 (Box 14, Folder 358)
        - Q, undated (Box 14, Folder 359)
        - J.M. Quinby and Co., 1896 (Box 14, Folder 360)
        - R, 1888-1913 (Box 15, Folder 361)
        - Rochester Cold Storage & Ice Co., 1902-13 (Box 15, Folder 362-363)
        - J.M. Rockwell, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 364)
        - Fannie Rous, 1888-1902, undated (Box 15, Folder 365)
        - Fred P. Rush & Co., 1888-91 (Box 15, Folder 366)
        - S, 1886-1913, undated (Box 15, Folder 367-368)
        - Seaboard National Bank, 1888-1913 (Box 15, Folder 369)
        - Seal Harbor Village Improvement Society, 1902-13 (Box 15, Folder 370)
        - Secor and Bell, 1910-12 (Box 15, Folder 371)
        - Sheppey & Co., 1896 (Box 15, Folder 372)